Maurice Neufeld Additional Files /4229
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Maurice Neufeld Additional Files
1944-1998
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Neufeld, Maurice F.
/4229
10 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8056629
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 23, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 04, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Professor Maurice Frank Neufeld (October 27, 1910 -April 10, 2003) was an American academic, author, union organizer and Army officer. In 1945, he was one of the two founding faculty members of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, appointed by its founding dean, Irving Ives.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers /4176: Maurice Neufeld Additional Papers /3007 AV: Maurice Neufeld "Grass Roots Founders and Grass Root Prodders: The Sources of Venture and Renewal for Democratic Education" Speech Audio-Visual Materials /4131m: Maurice Neufeld Additional Papers 5777: Maurice Neufeld Documents and Clipping Files /4229: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files /4230: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files 5515: Maurice F. Neufeld Collection of New York Times Clippings 5885: New York Times Additional Clipping File
Neufeld, Maurice F.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8056629
- Correspondence and records. (Box 1)
  - Agents, Publishers, Copyright, 1940-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1997-1998 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diary Copy Part 1, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diary Copy Part 2, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Neufield D,M.F. & H.C. - 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Neufeld, H.C. and M.F. Photographs and Negatives, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Scope and Contents
    12 Negative Photographs
  - Military Government, 1960-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photos and unpublished literary manuscript. (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1928-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    100+ Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 2)
    54 Photographs
  - The Shirt on Your Back (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
    20+ Photographs
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1942-1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photos. (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 1)
    (Man wearing Suit)
  - Photographs, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Maurice F. Neufeld; Notes (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Photographs (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Family photos. (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 1913-1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1922-1929 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Over 50 Photographs
  - Photographs, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    50+ Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diplomas (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 9)
    10+ Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photos. (Box 5)
  - Negatives, 1944-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    15+ Negative Photographs
  - Photographs, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    10 Photographs
  - Photographs, 1944-1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 4)
    2 Photographs
  - Photographs (Children) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    6 Photographs
  - Photographs, 1956-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    30+ Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - From Charlie Polette (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photograph (Box 5, Folder 9)
    1 Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 10)
    25+ Photographs
  - Photographs & FDR (Box 5, Folder 11)
    8 Photographs
- Correspondence and official papers. (Box 6)
  - Neufeld, H.C. -- Mem. Service, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Neufeld, H.C. -- Condolences, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Neufeld, H.C. -- Death, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Neufeld, H.C. -- Education, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Neufeld, H.C. -- Experience, 1962-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Neufeld, Maurice -- Education & Exper., 1976-1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Neufeld, M.F. -- Ed&Ex.-College Exper., 1927-1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Neufeld, M.F. -- ILR Archives, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Neufeld, M.F. -- Lib. Congress, 1958-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Neufeld, M.F. -- Johnson Mus, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Neufeld, Maurice World War 2 Official Record, 1942-1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Neufeld, Maurice - Writings, 1952-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Travel - Martha's Vineyard - Corres., 1967-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Books. (Box 7)
  - The Sky is Red, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Moments of Economic Freedom" by William Taft, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "History of Trade Unionism" Webb, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Madam Secretary France Perkins", 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kodak Photographs (Box), 1958-1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Maurice F. Neufeld The Queen of the West, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Contribution of the World's Columbian Exposition of 1893 to the Idea of a Planned Society in the United States (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Literary Manuscripts (including 1st and 2nd revisions of Persistence of Memory). (Box 9)
  - "The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Realms of Thought and Organized Labor in the Age of Jackson (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Realms of Thought and Organized Labor in the Age of Jackson" (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Realms of Thought and Organized Labor in the Age of Jackson (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Persistence of Ideas in the American Labor Movement (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Copy 4 Original MS (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Copy 4 Original MS Vol. 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Copy 4 Original MS Vol. 3 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Literary Manuscripts (including 4th revision of Persistence of Memory). (Box 10)
  - Macintosh Computer Guide (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fourth Revision Persistence Notes, 1978-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Fourth Revision Persistence Introduction -- Chapter I-IV (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Revision Persistence Chapters V-XIII, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hinda Cohen Neufeld, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Copy 4 Original MS Vol 4 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Contribution of the World's Columbian Exposition of 1893 to the Idea of a Planned Society in the United States, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Contribution of the World's Columbian Exposition of 1893 to the Idea of a Planned Society in the United States, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Maurice F. Neufeld Poetry, Translations, Short Stories, 1927-1930 (Box 10, Folder 9)